Apparently, it originated in ancient Egypt 3,000 years ago.
Children used to fashion dried grape vines into hula hoops and hoop with them.
I bet that was light and hard.
Yeah.
Well, back in the 50s, you probably remember the big hoop craze, or maybe you don't remember.
Oh yeah, Wham-O.
They created the first plastic hula hoop.
Maybe your parents did it as a kid.
That was the big hoop craze and then I guess it started to creep back into the American culture in the early 90s.
Yeah, early 90s or late 80s probably.
The hoops we use now are much cooler.
Much heavier.
This craze is absolutely taking over the world.
It is so much fun.
It's such a great way to bond with people and to have a great time.
We really recommend you getting hoop like this.
You can get it off of our website.
firegroove.com.
It's a little bit heavier.
That's the history of the hoop.
Let's move on.